

Reza Soleymani

Title: **Embedded Software Developer** Education: Electronic Engineering (Communication

Systems)

Area of expertise: Automotive and IoT industries

Contact: Christian Lindgren

076 004 50 01

Christian.lindgren@guokka.se

Reza is an Embedded Systems Software Engineer with over 7 years of experience in the Automotive and Embedded Systems fields. He possesses proficiency in C/C++, Python, Machine Vision, and Embedded Systems. Reza has gained substantial experience by actively working in the automotive and IoT industries, making valuable contributions to diverse projects. His expertise in Embedded Systems extends to various applications, including machine vision and the development of function testers for End-of-Line testing of ECUs, Infotainment systems, and other automotive components. Reza demonstrates a self-motivated mindset, meticulous attention to detail, and a strong ability to work effectively both independently and as part of a team. He is enthusiastic about sharing his best practices and equally receptive to learning from others.

COMPFTENCE

- Proficiency in Programming Languages (C/C++, Python, QT, QML)
- Embedded Software Development
- Problem Solving and Debugging
- User Interface Development
- Communication Protocols
- Cross-compilation
- Creative, Enthusiastic, Driven
- Team Collaboration

WORK EXPERIENCE

2021.05 - ongoing SGI Company (IoT), Embedded Systems Software Engineer

Assignment: Development of Cloud-based Infrastructure for Fire Alert Systems, Access Control and Video Management Systems.

Tasks:

- Developing Hardware-in-the-Loop (HIL) tests to assess the safety and performance of the fire alert system.
- Developing a Micro-service to collect the system status using the TCP protocol, based on the requirement Data-Model.
- Designing a Cloud architecture using Service-Oriented Architecture and ZeroMQ, that can handle more than 50 camera and fire alert system.
- Developing a cross-platform user interface using Qt/QML based on Material Design Standard.
- Implementing unit tests for all functions and endpoints.



Telefon: 076 0028 000 Mail: kontakt@quokka.se Hemsida: www.guokka.se

2017.06 - 2021.05 Crouse (Automotive), Embedded Software Developer

Assignment: Design and develop applications and tester devices for manufacturing end-of-line and automotive parts.

Tasks:

- Designing and developing machine vision systems and function testers based on Embedded Linux for end-of-line testing of ECU, Infotainment and PCB Boards.
- Designing and developing a modern UI for a digital instrument cluster using embedded Linux and Qt/QML, and tested by connecting to the Electronic Control Unit (ECU) using an OBD (On-Board Diagnostics) interface in Qt.
- Designing and developing 3 function tester devices for Automotive Column Levers.
- Developing Indoor Location Service based on UWB modules and STM32.

2015.03 - 2017.06 Kahroba Company, Embedded Software Developer

Assignment: Development of Flight and Car Simulators.

Tasks:

 Developing and designing a 3 Degree of Freedom flight and car simulator using an ARM MCU, motion control, servo motors, and a game

EDUCATION

2015-2017

MSc. Electronic Engineering (Communication Systems) Urmia University, Iran

Orientation: Signal Processing

Thesis: Deep Learning-Based Method for Classification of Mental Illness

Using FMRI Data and MATLAB.

LANGUAGES		IAGES	COMPUTER SKILLS		OTHER
	English	••••	C/C++	•••••	Iranian Driving license, type B
	Persian	•••••	Python	•••••	
	Turkish	•••••	Embedded Linux	•••••	
			QT/QML	•••••	
			MATLAB	••••	
			FreeRTOS	••••	
			Tensorflow	•••○○	
			Signal Processing	•••○○	
			OpenCV	••••	
			MongoDB	••••	
			Git/Gitlab	•••○○	
			Docker	•••○○	
			Javascript	••••	



Telefon: 076 0028 000 Mail: kontakt@quokka.se Hemsida: www.quokka.se Org. nr. 559322-6508